Dagmawi Yesuf

💌 daginaruto@gmail.com 📞 +251973004627 💡 Addis Ababa, Ethiopia 🥆 Portfolio in LinkedIn 📢 Github

Summary

I am a dedicated 4th year software Engineering student passionate about problem solving and machine learning. A Proven group leader having led multiple projects to completion looking forward to opportunities to grow as a software engineer.

I have solved over 300 questions in total on platforms like Leetcode ☑ and Codeforces ☑.

Technical skills

Python • Dart • Java • JavaScript • Html • Css

Frameworks and Technologies

Flutter	•	•	•	•	
Node JS	•	•			
React	•	•			
Figma	•	•	•	•	
MongoDB	•	•			

Projects

Rate Eat 🛮

June 2022 - September 2022

- A platform that allows users to give and consume item specific reviews and show growth points of businesses.
- Stood third place in the A2SV real world problem solving competition.
- Participated in the Frontend development and UI design as part of a team of 50.

InternSuit 🛮

April 2022 - July 2022

Worked on a mobile application platform which servers as an agent to help university students find companies that provides internship offers in Ethiopia.

Ethio Students Aid

September 2022 - May 2022

A platform or a site where students from high school, middle school or college have free access to educational information about different kinds of opportunities they can get from this world.

Awards

Regional Award for Higher Education Exam(top 0.2% highest score of 350,000 students)

Regional Government of Oromia 27th August 2016

Champion of the Ebenezer high Chess competition

Ebenezer Senior highschool 23rd May 2017

Education

Bachelor of Software Engineering

Addis Ababa University 🛮

September 2019 - present | Addis Ababa, Ethiopia 6th best in Africa.

Courses taken:

• Object Oriented Programming, Data structure and Algorithms, Database, Operating System, Mobile App and Web development.

Coding academy

Africa to Silicon Valley 🛮

December 2021 - present | Addis Ababa, Ethiopia A2SV upskills high-potential African students, connects with top silicon valley companies and creates digital solutions to urgent problems in their home countries. A2SV students have achieved 70% (31/44) success rate in 2022 at Google Software Engineering interviews.

Professional Experience

Frontend Developer

Africa to Silicon Valley 🛮

June 2022 - present | Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

- Designed, developed, and tested a platform that allows users to give and consume item specific reviews and show growth points of businesses.
- Participated in the Frontend development and UI design.
- Used platforms such Trello, ClickUp and Figma on a daily
- Judged by Dr. Jelani Nelson ♂, Ricardo Baeza-Yates ♂ and others.

Assistant Head of Community Education

Africa to Silicon Valley 🛮

February 2022 - present | Addis Ababa, Ethiopia Had the role of monitoring student activities as well as providing mentorship to students in developing their programming skills on a daily basis.

Social Media Manager

Africa to Silicon Valley 🛭

February 2022 – present | Addis Ababa, Ethiopia Worked on creating content as well as manage all the social media platforms A2SV | Africa to Silicon Valley owns. Which includes: Instagram, LinkedIn,

Telegram, Twitter.

Interests

Competitive programming, Artificial intelligence, 3D modeling, Hiking

Languages

Amharic

English



